[ERWIN]
Let's move!
[HANGE grunts]
Hange?
Get, get me a horse.
Section Commander!
Where're you going?
Back to the village
where we caught
the Titan that couldn't walk.
Not Ragako!
I need to see.
Have you lost touch
with reality?
You're in no condition
to ride horseback right now!
There's something
important there.
I feel it in my bones.
All right, fine.
I'll go myself.
You stay here
and quit trying to move!
Be on the lookout!
All riders assume formation!
[MIKASA]
Eren.
♪ Opening Song
[REINER]
You're awake.
Welcome back.
[Gasps]
[Breathe heavily]
What the hell? My arms!
[YMIR]
Eren.
I'm, uh, not in any
better shape here.
Seems we're both
having a shit day.
Ymir. What did they...
What did they do to me?
[REINER] Sorry. That was...
That was my fault.
You can pin
your injuries on me.
Guess I was in kind of
a hurry back there.
Bit your nape without
thinking about your arms.
Is that right? So. I lost.
Eren! Don't do it!
Easy there, hothead.
Take a look at where we are.
This is the giant forest
within Wall Maria.
Wall Rose is leagues away.
Which means...
we're deep in the heart
of Titan country. See?
I think our buddy
down there is an abnormal.
It may look like
he's just kickin' back,
but those eyes
haven't left us once.
Lot of smaller ones
down there, too.
That's plenty bad enough.
Another big one over there.
Fixated but
keeping his distance.
Strikes me as the shy type.
And then there are
these chumps.
Dirty bastards.
They had the foresight
to suit up in full gear.
'Course Reiner took yours.
Point is, changing into
a Titan isn't gonna
accomplish very much right now.
One, they can do
the same thing if they want.
Two, they can zip
into the trees if not.
Three, we're basically
surrounded on all sides.
Power or no power, getting out
of this would be tricky as hell,
even at the best of times.
Y'read me?
There's nothing to gain
by being a dumbass.
[REINER]
She's right.
Y'can't turn into Titans
right now anyway.
Don't count on that ability
coming to the rescue.
The body can only take so much.
It's a little preoccupied
with healing at the moment.
Nice try. You expect
me to sit here
and take the word of liar?
Yeah, well. We're sort of
at a disadvantage here.
It's not like we know the ins
and outs of how this works.
Unlike you guys,
I'm basically clueless
about the whole thing.
Hey, Reiner.
You said you'd start
talking once Eren was up.
Don't'cha think it's
about time somebody explains
what you plan on doing with us?
[REINER] We're taking you
to our hometown.
Of course, I realize neither of
you is just gonna do as I ask.
Like Ymir was saying, though,
this place is crawling with
Titans. They're everywhere.
We could beat the living
shit out of each other
if that's what you want.
But I wouldn't recommend it.
Our friends
down below are hungry
and not prone to discriminate.
[REINER] Whether you try to
cut and run or stick around,
believe me when I say
our options are limited.
We wait for nightfall.
So, why didn't you
just stay in Titan form
and run all the way home?
What's the point of stopping
here in the first place?
You get winded
and have to take a break?
Why don't you
use your imagination?
[YMIR sighs]
[EREN] Let me think.
Suppose I wait for an opening.
If I assume Titan form,
running away wouldn't really
be that much of a challenge.
Question is, can I assume
Titan form in this condition?
Reiner doesn't seem to think so,
and it's not like he
and Bertholdt would risk
stopping here
without a good reason.
What if I couldn't
transform to full strength?
Does that mean the other Titans
would be able to eat me?
So we're just gonna
sit on our asses
till the sun goes down?
[REINER]
It's a possibility.
[EREN] No. Why give us
the chance to recover?
If they wait for nightfall
we'd only be harder to rein in.
They'll make their move
while we're still helpless.
At this rate I can't
do anything. We're screwed.
[Gasps]
What happened
to everyone else?
Where are the Scouts?
Don't tell me they're
coming here to save us.
Oh god. If they show up,
none of 'em will--
Wait a second.
Those Titans at the castle
had no problem
moving around at night.
What's stopping these guys?
[REINER] The Titans here
can't move after dark.
But then you know all
about that, don't you, Ymir?
[EREN] How is it she's able
to transform into a Titan?
Doesn't seem to catch her
off-guard like it did me.
What's her angle?
Who's side is
she on in all this?
If I thought she was
hard to read before...
I've made up my mind.
I need information.
Anything I can get.
Keep my eyes and ears open.
When the moment comes,
make a break for it.
Before I can do that, though...
I have to keep
my emotions in check.
Give myself a chance
to recuperate.
[Gunshot]
Titan spotted at three o'clock!
Use the flare!
We've got a smoke shell
fired from the right wing!
We stay the course!
Tell the right wing
to merge with the center
and maintain direction!
The shortest path
is our only option.
Straight ahead.
We have until sundown!
[HANNES]
Mikasa. Hey, Mikasa. Hello?
Stop pushing so hard.
You're drifting up
into the vanguard.
You wanna break
the whole formation?
Look, I know how you feel.
But what'd I tell ya?
Eren's not gonna
let those assholes
get the best of him
without a fight.
Agreed?
[MIKASA]
Mm.
Kid just doesn't
have it in him to give up.
All we gotta do
is have a little faith.
He'll hold his own
till the rest of us get there.
Always has, always will.
[YMIR sighs]
Hey, Reiner. Got any water?
Help a girl out.
I'm dying over here.
[REINER] Sorry, there's not
a helluva a lot I can do.
Even if it is a matter
of life and death.
That's comforting.
Well, at least now we know
where we stand. Sort of.
[REINER] Speaking of which.
We've been working
our assess off. No food,
no sleep, no nothing.
Ever since
those Titans showed up.
That was yesterday, right?
Man, we're lucky the wall
hasn't been destroyed.
Still, you'd think that means
they'd give us a break.
And don't even get me
started on promotion.
What the hell?
What? Aww, come on.
I don't think that's
too much to ask, do you?
God knows we've done
our share of heavy lifting
all things considered.
I mean, I get it,
we're soldiers. Duty first.
It's just nice
to be acknowledged.
You bang your head
or something?
What're you even
talking about. Seriously?
Ugh. Don't give me that.
I'm not sayin' we
storm in and demand
the rank of captain
or anything.
[YMIR]
No. That's not what I mean.
[REINER] Oh, yeah. Where'd you
find that cannon, by the way?
I owe you one
for saving my bacon.
[YMIR exhales]
[REINER] Really nice of Christa
to patch me up afterwards.
I'm starting to think me
and her might become a thing.
[EREN]
Hey.
Right? It's not just me?
She always treats me
like we're--
[EREN]
Hey!
What's wrong with you?
You've got to be kidding me.
Huh? What're you so
pissed about all of a sudden?
Take it easy, man. Was it
something I said, or?
If you wanna die,
then just keep talking!
[YMIR]
Hold up, Eren.
I think somebody's
gone off the deep end.
Is that what this is, Bertholdt?
If you know something we don't,
now would be a good time
to put it on the table.
Huh?
[BERTHOLDT]
Reiner. Snap out of it.
You're not a soldier, okay?
You and I are... We're warriors.
[REINER breathe quaveringly]
[MARCO]
Reiner! What are you doing?
[MARCO screams and gasps]
[REINER]
Hey. Why...?
[BERTHOLDT gasps]
Why is Marco... being devoured?
Right. I see.
That's how things are.
[sobs softly]
What the hell's he doing?
I have a pretty good idea.
At least I think so.
Didn't add up at first.
Why would the man
who broke the wall
risk his neck to save Conny?
It's like the poor
bastard's personality is
compartmentalized.
Everything he does is
a contradiction in terms.
He can't help it.
On one hand,
he's a warrior bent on
pushing mankind past the brink.
On the other he's
pretending to be a solider.
I'm thinking maybe he got
a little lost in the role.
See. He can't resolve
those facets of himself.
Can't bear the weight
of what he's done.
The only way for him
to manage his conscience
is to fall for his own act.
He thinks he is a soldier.
This is what you call
a split personality.
He's gone insane.
His heart and mind
are at war with each other,
and judging by
Bertholdt's expression,
this isn't the first stalemate.
Blows me away!
Wow, someone as brutally honest
as you losing their grip--
[REINER]
Shut up! Not another word.
I'm sorry.
Must've really hit a nerve.
[EREN]
Is this some kind of joke?
Where do you get off
pretending to be the victim?
You're wallowing in self-pity?
How dare you. What was
going through your head
the day I told you
my story, huh?
Remember that, Bertholdt?
I'm talking to you, lackey!
I told you everything.
You sat there and looked me
straight in the eye.
Watched me relive seeing
my mother eaten alive.
[EREN]
Stop it! No!
Don't you remember?
Well, it just so happens
the chunk of wall
you kicked out
fell on our house.
It's what kept her from
being able to run away.
Ring any bells? Take you back?
Let me ask you again.
What was going through your head
when I told you that story?
Want me to be honest?
In the moment I felt...
sorry for you.
[EREN]
Huh. Sorry for me?
So, then. You're not...
You're not warriors or soldiers.
You're just murderers.
Psychotic mass-murderers
who snuffed out the lives
of countless people that
never did you any wrong.
Don't you think
I'm aware of that fact?
I don't need you shoving it
down my goddamn throat!
Then stop acting
like you've got any right
to feel sorry for yourself!
We're living in a hell
you two created!
Are you proud of yourselves?
You're not one of us!
You've never been!
You're not even human anymore!
[REINER]
You want an apology?
Is that what you hope to get
out of calling us murderers?
Want us to feel bad?
Want us to take the blame?
Who are you talking to?
The people you thought
you knew don't exist!
They're dead! But hey,
if screaming does it for ya,
go ahead and scream
your goddamn head off!
[REINER panting]
[EREN]
You're right.
Who am I? What do I know?
Still. I've got to do
something. Anything.
I swear to you,
one way or another,
the two of you will pay.
And it's gonna hurt.
[YMIR]
You can't be for real.
Huh?
Eren, grow up.
Keep spouting off
childish bullshit like that
and I've got no hope for you.
[EREN grunts]
[YMIR]
Tell me something.
What's with the giant monkey?
[REINER] Monkey?
What're you talking about?
Huh. I thought
for sure you'd know.
That's surprising. From the way
you guys were ogling it
all slack-jawed
I figured we were seeing
some kind of living legend.
Weird.
A monkey? Don't be cute.
Shut up and listen.
Monkey, Beast Titan.
Whatever you wanna call him,
he's behind this latest fiasco.
It's why Titans are
cropping up out of nowhere.
I get the feeling
he's gauging our strength.
Reiner and Betholdt are
trying to get wherever he is.
It's how they're
getting back home.
Feel free to correct me
if I'm way off base.
[Gasps]
Wait. How did you know?
Who are you?
What else haven't you told me?
Be patient. I'm caught up
in circumstances of my own.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
Eren. If you think
killing these morons
will put an end to all of this,
you are sorely mistaken.
[EREN]
Huh? But then who's the enemy?
The enemy?
Look, if I told you,
things would get too--
[REINER] Ymir! There's no future
for this world and you know it.
[YMIR gasps]
[REINER] You have
a solid grasp of things.
What d'you think comes next?
Joining our side wouldn't
be out of the question
if you were so inclined.
[YMIR] And put my faith
in you guys? That's rich.
Neither of you trusts me
as far as you can throw me.
[REINER]
Come on. That isn't true.
We know what you really want.
All you care about
is protecting Christa.
If we can all agree on that,
I don't see the conflict.
I'm being absolutely serious.
Is it so hard to believe we
want what's best for her, too?
Hate to break it to ya,
but you're not the only one.
Then again, you could always
put your trust in Eren,
see where that leads you.
What?
[REINER] You're probably
leaning toward escape.
Better to take a chance with him
than throw in with us, right?
Because if we
end up taking you,
there's not much hope
of being rescued.
I'll be straight with you.
That much is true.
Even if you came willingly,
we're not in a position
to guarantee your safety.
But if it's Christa
we're talking about,
we might be able
to do something.
[YMIR Gasps and snarls]
[REINER] It's your call.
What's it gonna be?
Is it Christa's future?
Or your own petty existence?
[EREN] Is there really
no future for this world?
Why? And the monkey.
How does he figure into this?
Come clean!
Who's the real enemy?
Tell me what you know!
Who is it?!
[YMIR sighs]
Couldn't say.
[EREN grunts]
[REINER]
All right, then. Sorry, Eren.
[Distant gunshot]
[BERTHOLDT]
The Scouts are here? Already?
[REINER grunts]
Son of a bitch!
[EREN]
No. Damn you, Ymir!
[EREN] Only one hour
left until sunset.
♪ Closing Song